Guide to the Tamiment Library Newspapers PERIODICALS.001
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Tamiment Library Newspapers
1873-2014
1960-1990
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Tamiment Library
Henle, John
PERIODICALS.001
290 Linear Feet in 657 boxes
The collection contains some 1,717 titles to date (April 2014). They were published by international and local labor unions in the United States and Canada, radical political parties (Anarchist, Communist, Maoist, Socialist, Trotskyist), the New Left, and by organizations representing civil rights movements (African-Americans, prisoners, etc.), peace movements, protest against the war in Vietnam (including titles published by American soldiers), activity in support of national liberation movements, student and youth activism, the counterculture, feminism and gay liberation, and other activism. While most of the titles are from the U.S., and of these about one fourth are from New York State, there are also some foreign titles, most from Western Europe, primarily Great Britain, France, Italy and Spain. The holdings continue to grow through donations and subscriptions. While the majority of the titles lack catalog records in BobCat, NYU's electronic library catalog, retrospective cataloging is taking place. An unpublished guide available in the library shows holdings information for each title.
Custodial History
Newspapers in this collection have been accumulated by the Tamiment Library through various donations and subscriptions.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is currently closed while the material is processed. Material will be available for access in new collections by August 2018; some titles contained within this collection will be available for research in early 2018.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Newspapers in this collection have been compiled by the Tamiment Library. The accession number associated with these materials is 1950.028.
Some materials were donated by John Henle in 2016. The accession number associated with this gift is 2016.016.
Historical/Biographical Note
The Tamiment Library's collection of newspapers from labor and activist organizations traces its origins to the library of the Rand School of Social Science, established in 1906. Located just off Union Square in New York City, the Rand School was a workers education institution supported by the Socialist Party of New York, the garment trades unions, the Workman's Circle, and the Jewish Forward Association. The Rand School taught courses in economics, economic history, U.S. history, literature, socialist theory, and labor-management relations. In the mid-1920s the Rand School established a Trade Union Institute to train people interested in careers in trade union organizing and administration. The school also sponsored a vast array of cultural programs: theatre groups, poetry readings, and a workers chorus.
The Rand School's library, which was renamed the Meyer London Memorial Library in 1926, after the Socialist Congressman from Manhattan's Lower East Side, always played an important role in the school. By the 1930s it had one of the finest collections New York City documenting the history of labor and the left. In addition to the book collections many of the unions and progressive organizations associated with the school placed copies of their newspapers, journals, newsletters, leaflets, broadsides, and ephemeral pamphlet literature with the Library. By the end of World War II the Library had a large and growing collection of both current and historical newspapers. However, by the early 1950s the school was in financial trouble and it closed in 1956. For the next seven years the Meyer London Library was maintained with a subsidy from the Tamiment Institute, the educational arm of Camp Tamiment, a socialist summer camp in Pennsylvania's Pocono mountains.
In 1963 the Library was given to New York University. Under NYU administration the Tamiment Library grew rapidly, and today it has nearly 75,000 monograph volumes, a serial collection with more than 8,500 titles, a printed ephemera collection of nearly a million items, and 15,000 linear feet of archives, including personal papers, labor union records, photographs, film, graphics, and oral histories. The newspapers are part of the Library's serial collection. The holdings continue to grow through current subscriptions and donations of historical material.
Sources:
Swanson, Dorothy, "The Tamiment Institute/Ben Josephson Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives at New York University," Library Quarterly, 59:2 (1989), 148-161.
Scope and Content Note
As of April 2014, the collection contains some 1,717 titles published by international and local labor unions in the United States and Canada, radical political parties (Anarchist, Communist, Maoist, Socialist, Trotskyist), the New Left, and by organizations representing civil rights movements (African-Americans, prisoners, etc.), peace movements, protest against the war in Vietnam (including titles published by American soldiers), activity in support of national liberation movements, student and youth activism, the counterculture, feminism and gay liberation, and other activism. While most of the titles are from the U.S., and of these about one third are from New York State, there are also some foreign titles, most from Western Europe, primarily Great Britain, France, Italy and Spain. The holdings continue to grow through donations and subscriptions. While the majority of the titles lack catalog records in BobCat, NYU's electronic library catalog, retrospective cataloging is taking place. An unpublished guide available in the library shows holdings information for each title.
Arrangement
Arranged Alphabetically.
Titles are arranged in one series.
Missing Title
Inventory
African Americans |x Civil rights |v Newspapers.; Anarchism |v Newspapers.; Anarchism |z United States |v Newspapers.; Civil rights |z United States |v Newspapers.; Labor unions |z United States |v Newspapers.; Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York |v Newspapers; Labor movement |z United States |x Newspapers.; Labor movement |z New York (State) |z New York |v Newspapers.; Prisoners |x Civil rights |z United States |v Newspapers.; Peace movements |z United States |v Newspapers.; New Left |z United States |v Newspapers.; National liberation movements |x Foreign public opinion, American |v Newspapers.; Socialism -- Newspapers.; Social movements |z United States |v Newspapers.; Radicalism |z United States |v Newspapers.; Puerto Ricans |x Civil rights |z United States |v Newspapers.; Newspapers.; Feminism |z United States |v Newspapers.; Communism |z United States |v Newspapers.; Counterculture |z United States |v Newspapers.; Communism |v Newspapers.; Indians of North America |x Civil rights |v Newspapers.; Labor |z New York (State) |z New York |v Newspapers.; Gay liberation movement |z United States |v Newspapers.; Hispanic Americans |x Civil rights |x Newspapers.; Soldiers |z United States |x Political activity |v Newspapers.; Student movements |z United States |v Newspapers.; Labor |z United States |v Newspapers.; Socialism -- United States -- Newspapers.; Vietnam War, 1961-1975 |x Protest movements |z United States |v Newspapers.; Youth movements -- United States -- Newspapers.; Underground newspapers |z United States.; Henle, John; Rand School of Social Science. Meyer London Memorial Library
- #-A
  - 1st Casualty City of publication: New York, N.Y. Publisher: Vietnam Veterans Against the War., 1971 (Box 2)
  - 1st Issue: The Newspaper of the Free Association Publisher: Free Association., 1975 (Box 134)
  - 19 Place of publication: New York, N.Y. Publisher: Committee for Independent Political Action, 1966 (Box 1)
  - 30 Day Notice Place of publication: Seattle, Wash. Publisher: The Union, 1983-1985 (Box 429)
  - 32 Events City of publication: Bronx, N.Y. Publisher: Building Service Employees, Local 32-E., 1968 (Box 426)
  - 32B-32J City of publication: New York, N.Y. Publisher: Local 32B-32J, Service Employees International Union, 1976-1996 (Box 426-427)
  - 70's Biweekly Place of publication: New York, N.Y., nd (Box 384B)
  - '76 Auto Contract: A Time to Fight: National Newsletter Place of publication: Detroit, Mich. Publisher: Auto Workers United to Fight in 76, 1976 (Box 31)
  - 338 News Place of publication: New York, N.Y. Publisher: Retail, Wholesale, Chain Store Food Employee Union, 1941-1989 (Box 429)
  - 400 Watchword: Official Publication, UAW Amalgamated Local 400 Place of publication: Detroit, Mich. Publisher: UAW Amalgamated Local 400, 1984 (Box 140)
  - 560 Free Press / Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen and Helpers Place of publication: Union City, N.J. Publisher: Int'l Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen & Helpers, Local 560, 1987-1989 (Box 139)
  - 840 News Place of publication: New York, N.Y. Publisher: Local 840, Teamsters, 1975-1984 (Box 123)
  - 1199 Save Our Union News Place of publication: New York, N.Y. Publisher: Save Our Union Coalition, 1984 (Box 128A)
  - 1199 SEIU News Place of publication: New York, N.Y. Publisher: National Health and Human Service Employees Union, SEIU, AFL-CIO, 2000-2004 (Box 128A)
  - 1397 Rank & File Place of publication: Homestead, Pa. Publisher: United Steelworkers of America, Local Union 1397, 1978 (Box 433)
  - A: rivista anarchica Place of publication: Milan, Italy Publisher: Editrice A, 1971-1974 (Box 487)
  - About Face Place of publication: Los Angeles, Calif. Publisher: GIs & Vietnam Vets Against the War, 1969 (Box 161)
  - About Face!: The U.S. Servicemen's Fund Newsletter Place of publication: New York, N.Y. Publisher: U.S. Servicemen's Fund, 1969-1972 (Box 161)
  - Aboveground Place of publication: Colorado Springs, Colo. Publisher: Aboveground, 1969-1970 (Box 161)
  - ACA News Place of publication: New York, N.Y. Publisher: Trade Union Service, 1962-1965 (Box 1)
  - Acero / Spain. Ejército Popular de la República. 5. Cuerpo. Place of publication: Spain Publisher: El Cuerpo, 1938 (Box 5)
  - Acorn News Place of publication: Little Rock, Ark. Publisher: Arkansas Community Organizations for Reform Now, 1977-1978 (Box 31)
  - Act: The RITA's Newsletter Place of publication: Paris, France Publisher: Act, 1968-1974 (Box 161)
  - Action Place of publication: Bronx, N.Y. Publisher: Northwest Bronx Community and Clergy Coalition, 1982 (Box 2)
  - Action Place of publication: Paris, France Publisher: Service des Comités d'Action, 1968 (Box 2)
  - Action Place of publication: New York, N.Y. Publisher: United Federation of College Teachers, 1964-1972 (Box 2)
  - Action (ACT) Place of publication: New York, N.Y. Publisher: United Federation of College Teachers, 1968 (Box 2)
  - Activist Place of publication: U.S.A. Publisher: United Committee Against the War, 1966 (Box 2)
  - Activist Place of publication: Buffalo, N.Y. Publisher: Buffalo Youth Against War and Fascism, 1969-1971 (Box 2)
  - Activist: Newspaper of the ACT for Disarmament Coalition Place of publication: Toronto, Canada Publisher: ACTIVIST Collective, 1986 (Box 2)
  - ADA World Place of publication: Washington, D.C. Publisher: Americans for Democratic Action, 1971-1982 (Box 1)
  - L'Adunata dei refrattari = Call of the refractaires Place of publication: New York, N.Y. Publisher: Constantino Zonchello, 1946-1950 (Box 3-4)
  - Advance Place of publication: Birmingham, Ala. Publisher: Trade Union Action League, 1983-1985 (Box 5)
  - Advance: Official Organ of the ACWA Place of publication: New York, N.Y. Publisher: Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America, 1969-1976 (Box 5)
  - Aero-Notes / Local 365 Place of publication: Newark, N.J. Publisher: Local 365, U.A.W.-C.I.O., 1943-1945 (Box 5)
  - AFGE Government Standard Place of publication: Washington, D.C. Publisher: American Federation of Government Employees, 1985-2002 (Box 25)
  - AFL Weekly News Service Place of publication: Washington, D.C. Publisher: American Federation of Labor, 1951 (Box 5)
  - AFL-CIO News Place of publication: Washington, D.C. Publisher: American Federation of Labor and Congress of Industrial Organizations, 1956-1984 (Box 5)
    General
    Researchers must use microfilm (Film R-7040)
  - The African World Place of publication: Greensboro, N.C. Publisher: Youth Organization for Black Unity, 1974 (Box 5)
  - After the Fall Place of publication: New York, N.Y. Publisher: After the Fall Collective, nd (Box 5)
  - Against the Grain Place of publication: New York, N.Y. Publisher: Against the Grain Collective, 1976-1978 (Box 5)
  - L'Agitazione del Sud Place of publication: Palermo, Italy Publisher: L'Agitazione del Sud, 1964-1969 (Box 6)
  - L'Aiguilleur: la voix de l'ACWA Place of publication: Montreal, Canada Publisher: Montreal Joint Board of the ACWA, 1952-1957 (Box 1)
  - Ain't I a Woman? Place of publication: Iowa City, Iowa Publisher: Publications Collective, Iowa City WLF, 1970-1973 (Box 6)
  - AKI Nueva York Place of publication: New York, N.Y. Publisher: ECOS, 1955 (Box 6)
  - Akron Beacon Journal Place of publication: Akron, Ohio Publisher: Beacon Journal Co., 1978 (Box 6)
  - Akwesasne Notes Place of publication: Roseveltown, N.Y. Publisher: Jerry Gambill, 1969-1975 (Box 7)
  - Alarm Place of publication: Chicago, Ill. Publisher: International Workingmen's Association, 1885-1888 (Box 513)
    Researchers must use microfilm (Film R-7950)
  - Al-Awda Place of publication: New Brunswick, N.J. Publisher: New Jersey Solidarity-Activists for the Liberation of Palestine, 2005 (Box 6)
  - Alderson Hospitality House Place of publication: U.S.A., 1983 (Box 341)
  - Alert: Performing Artists for Nuclear Disarmament Place of publication: New York, N.Y. Publisher: Performing Artists for Nuclear Disarmament, nd (Box 8)
  - Alive Magazine: Literature & Ideology Place of publication: Guelph, Canada Publisher: Alive Production Collective, 1975?-1976 (Box 8)
  - All Hands Abandon Ship! Place of publication: Newport, R.I. Publisher: BuRevPers, 1971-1972 (Box 161)
  - All Ready on the Left Place of publication: Vista, Calif. Publisher: All Ready on the Left, 1970-1971 (Box 161)
  - All You Can Eat Place of publication: New Brunswick, N.J. Publisher: All You Can Eat Collective, 1970-1973 (Box 18)
  - Allegro Place of publication: New York, N.Y. Publisher: Associated Musicians of Greater New York, 1955-current (Box 9-17A)
  - Allied Industrial Worker Place of publication: Beverly Hills, Calif. Publisher: International Union, Allied Industrial Workers of America, 1985-1992 (Box 18)
  - Alliance, The Place of publication: Portland, Or. Publisher: Oregon Coalition of Alternative Human Services, 1985-1987 (Box 5)
  - The Ally Place of publication: Berkeley, Calif., 1968-1974 (Box 161)
  - Alternative Place of publication: U.S.A. Publisher: Naperville Central High School, 1970 (Box 281)
  - Alternative Theatre Place of publication: Baltimore, Md. Publisher: Theatre Project, Antioch College, 1975-1976 (Box 018A)
  - Alternative to Alienation Place of publication: Toronto Publisher: Alternative to Alienation, 1974-1975 (Box 19)
  - Alternative Vision Place of publication: La Jolla, Calif. Publisher: University of California, San Diego, 1989 (Box 29)
  - Amalgamated Laundry Workers Bulletin Place of publication: New York, N.Y. Publisher: Laundry Workers Joint Board of Greater New York, 1953-1961 (Box 1)
  - Amazing Grace Place of publication: Fla. Publisher: Florida Free Press, 1970-1971 (Box 19)
  - Amazon Place of publication: Milwaukee, Wis. Publisher: Amazon Collective, 1975-1979 (Box 19)
  - America @ Work Place of publication: Washington, D.C. Publisher: AFL-CIO Public Affairs Dept., 1996-2005 (Box 18A-18B)
  - America for All Place of publication: Chicago, Ill. Publisher: Socialist Party of America, 1932 (Box 19)
    Researchers must use microfilm (Film R-7276)
  - American Atheist Place of publication: Honolulu, Hawaii Publisher: Freethought Society of America, Inc., 1964-1966 (Box 26)
  - American Civil Liberties Union News Place of publication: New York, N.Y. Publisher: American Civil Liberties Union, 1957-1964 (Box 19)
  - American Labor Citizen Place of publication: San Francisco, Calif. Publisher: American Federation of Labor, 1939 (Box 487)
  - The American Marine Engineer Place of publication: Washington, D.C. Publisher: National Marine Engineers' Beneficial Association AFL-CIO, 1951-1990 (Box 20)
  - American Maritime Officer Place of publication: Brooklyn, N.Y. Publisher: Marine Engineers Beneficial Association, AFL-CIO, 1977 (Box 21)
  - American Mass Line Place of publication: Cleveland, Ohio Publisher: American Communist Workers Movement (Marxist-Leninist), 1970 (Box 237)
    Researchers must use microfilm (Film R-7897)
  - American Postal Worker Place of publication: Washington, D.C. Publisher: American Postal Workers Union (APWU), 1984-2002 (Box 21-24)
  - American Report Place of publication: New York, N.Y. Publisher: Clergy and Laity Concerned, 1971 (Box 237)
    Researchers must use microfilm (Film R-7232)
  - American Student Place of publication: Cleveland, Ohio Publisher: American Student Movement (Anti-Imperialist), 1970 (Box 238)
  - American Teacher Place of publication: Washington, D.C. Publisher: American Federation of Teachers, 1971-1993 (Box 25)
  - The American Teacher Place of publication: Chicago, Ill. Publisher: American Federation of Teachers, 1983-1986 (Box 25)
  - AMI: periodico del Servicio Sanitario Internacional (B.I.) Place of publication: Madrid, Spain Publisher: Servicio Sanitario Internacional (B.I.), 1937 (Box 19)
  - Amnesty Action Place of publication: New York, N.Y. Publisher: Amnesty International USA, 1979-1999 (Box 26)
  - An Phoblacht: Republican News Place of publication: Dublin Publisher: An Phoblacht, 1983 (Box 31)
  - Analysis Place of publication: New York, N.Y. Publisher: Analysis Associates, 1944-1957 (Box 29)
  - The Anarchist Place of publication: New York, N.Y. Publisher: Robert Steed, 1966 (Box 27)
  - Anarchy Place of publication: San Francisco, Calif., 1981-1992 (Box 27)
  - Anchorage Troop Place of publication: Anchorage, Alaska Publisher: Anchorage Troop, 1968-1972 (Box 161)
  - Andromeda Place of publication: Stillwater, Okla. Publisher: Andromeda International, Inc., 1971 (Box 27)
  - Ang Katipunan Place of publication: Oakland, Calif. Publisher: Union of Democratic Filipinos, 1977-1985 (Box 213-214)
  - Ann Arbor Argus Place of publication: Ann Arbor, Mich. Publisher: White Panther Community News Service, 1969-1971 (Box 29)
  - Ann Arbor Sun Place of publication: Ann Arbor, Mich. Publisher: Rainbow Peoples Party, 1971-1975 (Box 29)
  - Anti-Apartheid News Place of publication: London, England Publisher: Anti-Apartheid Movement, 1977-1978 (Box 29)
  - Anti-Fascist Front Place of publication: Oakland, Calif. Publisher: National Committees to Combat Fascism in America, 1969 (Box 38)
  - The Anvil Place of publication: Sacramento, Calif. Publisher: California Prisoners Union, 1971 (Box 341)
  - The Appeal to Reason Place of publication: Berkeley, Calif. Publisher: Alameda County Branch, Bay Area Local, of Social Democrats, USA, 1974-1988 (Box 29)
  - APWU NewService Place of publication: Washington, D.C. Publisher: American Postal Workers Union, 2002 (Box 300)
  - The Aquarian Place of publication: Montclair, N.J. Publisher: Aquarian Publishing Co., 1975-1976 (Box 29)
  - Arbitration Times Place of publication: New York, N.Y. Publisher: American Arbitration Association, 1990-1991 (Box 487)
  - The Arctic Arsenal Place of publication: Delta Junction, Alaska, 1971 (Box 161)
  - The Ark Place of publication: Houston, Tex., nd (Box 31)
  - ARM Place of publication: Berkeley, Calif. Publisher: American Revolutionary Movement, nd (Box 2)
  - Art & Artists Place of publication: New York, N.Y. Publisher: Foundation for the Community of Artists, 1983 (Box 31)
  - The Arts in Prison Place of publication: U.S.A., 1972 (Box 341)
  - As You Were Place of publication: Fort Ord, Monterey, Calif. Publisher: G.I.'s at Fort Ord Military Complex, 1969-1970 (Box 161)
  - Asheville Global Report Place of publication: Asheville, N.C. Publisher: Asheville Global Report, 2002 (Box 31)
  - Asianweek Place of publication: San Francisco, Calif. Publisher: Asian Week Pub. Co., 1992-1993 (Box 31A)
  - Assembler Place of publication: Linden, N.J. Publisher: Local 595, UAW, 1981 (Box 31)
  - Attica News Place of publication: Buffalo, N.Y. Publisher: Attica Now, 1975-1977 (Box 341)
  - Attica News Service Place of publication: Buffalo, N.Y. Publisher: Attica Defense Committee, 1973-1975 (Box 31)
  - Attitude Check Place of publication: Vista, Calif. Publisher: Movement for a Democratic Military, 1969-1970 (Box 161)
  - Augur Place of publication: Eugene, Or., 1971-1972 (Box 31)
  - Australasian Spartacist Place of publication: Sydney, Australia Publisher: Spartacist Publications, 1975-1977 (Box 399)
  - Auto Workers United to Fight National Newsletter Place of publication: Detroit, Mich. Publisher: Auto Workers United to Fight, 1977-1978 (Box 31)
  - Auto-Free Press Place of publication: New York, N.Y. Publisher: Auto-Free New York Committee of Transportation Alternatives, 1993 (Box 31)
  - Avante! Place of publication: Lisboa, Portugal Publisher: Partido Comunista Português, 1999 (Box 31)
  - Avatar Place of publication: Boston, Mass. Publisher: Avatar, Inc., 1968 (Box 31)
- B
  - B & C News Place of publication: Washington, D.C. Publisher: Bakery and Confectionery Workers' International Union of America, 1968-1972 (Box 32)
  - Babylon Place of publication: New York, N.Y. Publisher: Revolutionary Peoples Communications Network, 1971 (Box 23)
  - BAD Place of publication: Boston, Mass. Publisher: Y.M.I. INC., 1972-1973 (Box 23)
  - Bad Moon Rising Place of publication: New York, N.Y. Publisher: New York Students for a Democratic Society, nd (Box 34)
  - Bakers' and Confectioners' Journal Place of publication: Chicago, Ill. Publisher: Bakery and Confectionery Workers' International Union of America, 1945 (Box 32)
  - Bakery Workers Organize! Place of publication: New York, N.Y. Publisher: N.Y.-N.J. United Workers Organization Food Industry Committee, 1977 (Box 33)
  - Baltimore Independent Place of publication: Baltimore, Md. Publisher: Paine Pub. and Print. Co., 1971 (Box 37)
  - The Baltimore School: A Learning Network Place of publication: Baltimore, Md. Publisher: Baltimore School, nd (Box 34)
  - Bandiera Rossa Place of publication: N.Y. Publisher: Gruppi Comunisti Revoluzionari Sezione Italiana della IV Internazionale, 1967-1969 (Box 435)
  - Barb on Strike Place of publication: Berkeley, Calif. Publisher: Red Mountain Tribe, 1969 (Box 248)
  - Barb Wire Society Place of publication: Philadelphia, Pa., 1970 (Box 341)
  - Barrage Place of publication: Fort Bill Publisher: Department of Defense Directive, 1972 (Box 161)
  - Barricada Internacional: Official Voice of the Sandinista National Liberation Front Place of publication: Nicaragua Publisher: Sandinista National Liberation Front, 1984-1985 (Box 37)
  - Basta Ya Place of publication: San Francisco, Calif. Publisher: Los Siete de la Raza, 1969-1972 (Box 37)
  - A Batalha, 1975-1982 (Box 2)
  - Bay Area Painters News Place of publication: Oakland, Calif. Publisher: Brotherhood of Painters, Decorators and Paperhangers of America, Local Union No. 127, 1965-1973 (Box 32-33)
  - BC & T News / Bakery, Confectionery, and Tobacco Workers International Union Place of publication: Washington, D.C. Publisher: Bakery, Confectionery, and Tobacco Workers International Union, 1978-1998 (Box 34-36)
  - BCTGM Communicator Publisher: Bakery, Confectionery, Tobacco and Grain Millers Union, 1996-1999 (Box 36)
  - BCTGM News Place of publication: Kensington, Md. Publisher: Bakery, Confectionery, Tobacco and Grain Millers Union, 1999-2000 (Box 36)
  - Beacon Place of publication: New York, N.Y. Publisher: Esso Tanker-Men's Association, 1941 (Box 37)